Life has a mind of its own
The Soloist is a drama, music film directed by Joe Wright.
A Los Angeles journalist befriends a homeless Juilliard-trained
musician, while looking for a new article for the paper.
Steve Lopez, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Nathaniel Ayers, played by Jamie Foxx.
Mary Weston, played by Catherine Keener.
Graham Claydon, played by Tom Hollander.
David Carter, played by Nelsan Ellis.
Adam Crane, played by Michael Bunin.
The Soloist is a 2009 biographical drama film directed by Joe
Wright, and starring Jamie Foxx and Robert Downey Jr.
The plot is based on the true story of Nathaniel Ayers, a musician
who developed schizophrenia and became homeless.
Originally intended to be released on November 21, 2008, the
film was released in theaters on April 24, 2009.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed just
$38 million against its $60 million budget.
The film explores themes of newspaper, schizophrenia, musician, violin, cello.
The tone is emotional.